Surafel Melese Tariku

FullStack Developer

Addis Ababa surafelmelese09@gmail.com +251 92 173 3550

Hi there, this is Surafel. I graduated with Bachelor's in Software Engineering from Addis Ababa Institute of Technology with CGPA of 3.6 and have some 3+ years of experience working with Flutter, ASP, Nestjs and Django stacks.

In my 3+ years as a Flutter developer I worked on an ecommerce application specifically on Payment and Cinema modules and on an ecommerce app with delivery service. I'm also the author of two flutter packages.

In most of the projects I was involved in I had the chance to collaborate with different teams ranging from those who designed the components I worked on to those who implemented and supervised the QA process that made sure we shipped quality products.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Work Experience

Backend development - NestJS, GraphQL, Vendure.io

Pine Labs - Remote

March 2023 to Present

We build advanced e-commerce solutions and are big believers of open source. We don't do basic stuff for as cheap as possible, we create advanced e-commerce solutions at a fair price check us out at https://www.pinelabs.com/

Mobile Application Developer

Whale Technologies - Addis Ababa

March 2023 to Present

- Design and develop mobile applications
- Monitor the entire application development lifecycle (design, test, support, and release)
- Add and optimize features as per specifications
- Make and prepare releases of dynamic application components
- Create cross-platform applications for Android, iOS, Windows, etc.
- Work on software analysis, troubleshooting, and debugging
- Build interfaces to improve UX

Senior Software Engineer

eTech S.C - Addis Ababa February 2021 to Present

I'm working on an Ecommerce web application with vendure, the headless open source project, as the backend and Vuejs and Flutter on the front end

Full Stack Developer

twoMatches Corporation - Remote July 2022 to March 2023

twoMatches is a platform for sellers to network with other sellers to boost their store's sales. I'm worked on https://twomatches.xyz/ as Full Stack Developer.

Mobile Application Developer

Cnet Software Technologies - Addis Ababa September 2020 to March 2023

The Company CNET Software Technologies developes ERP systems. I worked on the mobile extension of the system which allows users make mobile payments, book events and buy tickets with companies using our ERP system.

Backend Developer

Independent - Remote May 2022 to June 2022

Django backend development for a chrome extension project that allows users to filter web pages based on user defined key words.

Education

Bachelor's degree in Software Engineering

Addis Ababa University - Addis Ababa 2016 to 2021

Skills

- Python (Programming Language)
- TensorFlow
- Java
- ASP.NET
- ASP.NET MVC
- Django REST Framework
- Django
- Flutter
- Dart
- Git
- APIs
- CSS
- MySQL
- User Interface (UI)
- Bootstrap
- GitHub

- Application Development
- Docker
- HTML5
- AIAX
- Android development
- JavaScript
- Android
- JSON
- Node.js
- Angular
- Vuejs
- Python
- SQL

Languages

- English Intermediate
- German Beginner
- Amharic Fluent

Links

http://dalyathan.netlify.app

http://linkedin.com/in/dalyathan

https://github.com/dalyathan

https://www.upwork.com/freelancers/~01a43f268fbeb1227d

Certifications and Licenses

Build Basic Generative Adversarial Networks

April 2021 to Present

- Learn about GANs and their applications
- Understand the intuition behind the fundamental components of GANs
- Explore and implement multiple GAN architectures
- Build conditional GANs capable of generating examples from determined categories

Tensorflow: Data And Deployment

March 2021 to Present

In this four-course Specialization, I learned how to get machine learning models into the hands of real people on all kinds of devices. I started by understanding how to train and run machine learning models in browsers and in mobile applications. Learnt how to leverage built-in datasets with just a

few lines of code, learnt about data pipelines with TensorFlow data services, used APIs to control data splitting, process all types of unstructured data, and retrained deployed models with user data while maintaining data privacy.

TensorFlow: Advanced Techniques

March 2021 to Present

The course helped me expand my knowledge of the Functional API and build exotic non-sequential model types. I learnt how to optimize training in different environments with multiple processors and chip types and get introduced to advanced computer vision scenarios such as object detection, image segmentation, and interpreting convolutions.

DeepLearning.Al TensorFlow Developer

February 2021 to Present

TensorFlow is one of the most in-demand and popular open-source deep learning frameworks available today. The DeepLearning.AI TensorFlow Developer Professional Certificate program taught me applied machine learning skills with TensorFlow so I can build and train powerful models.

Deep Learning

January 2021 to Present

The Deep Learning Specialization is a foundational program that helped me understand the capabilities, challenges, and consequences of deep learning and prepared me to participate in the development of leading-edge AI technology.

Machine Learning

December 2020 to Present

This course provides a broad introduction to machine learning, datamining, and statistical pattern recognition. Topics include: (i) Supervised learning (parametric/non-parametric algorithms, support vector machines, kernels, neural networks). (ii) Unsupervised learning (clustering, dimensionality reduction, recommender systems, deep learning). (iii) Best practices in machine learning (bias/variance theory; innovation process in machine learning and AI).

Front End Web Development With React

November 2020 to Present

This course explores Javascript based front-end application development, and in particular the React library (Currently Ver. 16.3). This course used JavaScript ES6 for developing React application. I got an introduction to the use of Reactstrap for Bootstrap 4-based responsive UI design. I was introduced to various aspects of React components. I learnt about React router and its use in developing single-page applications. I also learnt about designing controlled forms.

Front End Web UI Frameworks And Tools: Bootstrap 4

November 2020 to Present

This gave me an overview of client-side web UI frameworks, in particular Bootstrap 4. I learnt about grids and responsive design, Bootstrap CSS and JavaScript components. I also learnt about CSS preprocessors, Less and Sass, the basics of Node.js and NPM and task runners like Grunt and Gulp.

Publications

Time Duration Picker Dart plugin

 $\underline{https://pub.dev/packages/time_duration_picker}$

March 2022

A time picker for paired consecutive tasks. It lets you specify the icons for each of your actions and callbacks when the user rotates each icon. You can optionally give callback for the time duration, decorations for the knob, the knob background, the clock and also color for your icons. The time and duration values are not displayed by the TimeDurationPicker widget, instead they are passed to the callbacks provided.

Web Like Carousel Dart plugin

https://pub.dev/packages/rotating_carousel

March 2023

A simple package with a carousel widget having web look and feel. It let's you pass any number of widgets(yeah widgets, not just images) to be displayed. It also gives you control over how much of the cards containing your widgets you want to overlap(or not). It's lightweight and doesn't depend on any other packages.

Additional Information

Testimonials

"Surafel has been a great addition to the team. He is very focused and a great team player."

• Amos Omokpo, Two Matches Corporation, Co-founder and CEO

"Surafel was a highly efficient and knowledgeable developer. He navigated an erratic client schedule across multiple projects with a level of professionalism that is on par with the most veteran of contractors. I was very impressed with how fast he was able to implement changes. He was able to properly translate complex functionality and apply it into an application. His high skill set and positive attitude put my mind at ease knowing it was in very capable hands. Communication was easy and efficient which it is especially important when dealing with software. He was a valuable member of the team and I would definitely recommend him for anyone looking to hire him. I will absolutely be using his services again and would highly recommend him if asked."

• Chris Marlowe

"Surafel has been an incredible asset and a wonderful person to work with. We wish he could have stayed with us for longer but we definitely wish him the best in his future endeavours."

• Fanuel Abebe, Seniour Android Developer and Project Manager at CNET Software Technologies PLC

"Surafel has managed to lead our ecommerce team through incredible heights. He will forever have a place at our company".

• Million Yitbarek, Project Manager at Etech S.C